<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-08T10:02:28-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/</id><title type="html">Will you be my rubber duck?</title><subtitle>I like to talk to myself in public.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2018/01/08/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-01-08T01:24:23-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-08T01:24:23-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2018/01/08/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2018/01/08/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hypothetical Government</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/politics/speculation/2017/12/28/hypothetical-government.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hypothetical Government" /><published>2017-12-28T01:24:23-06:00</published><updated>2017-12-28T01:24:23-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/politics/speculation/2017/12/28/hypothetical-government</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/politics/speculation/2017/12/28/hypothetical-government.html">&lt;p&gt;Thinking a bit about what my fantasy form of government (I used to be a fan of direct democracy) nowadays would be, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally based on US model,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduce the number of congresspeople down to either 12 or 14. Similarly with the senate. Keep the president and court system as is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of voting by geographic area, these representatives would have their constituents randomly (but evenly) distributed throughout the entire country. So if you live with your spouse, you might be represented by senator 1, but they could be represented by senator 3. The only difference (in terms of elections) between congress and the senate would be term limits. Thus the highest level of government is incentivized only to act in the collective good, and has a much greater degree of accountability and ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accountability and ownership brings us to lower levels of government: state and city. I would try replacing democratically elected committees at both levels with democratically elected “tyrants”. Tyrants could be re elected over and over again ad infinitum, and would have all the authority currently invested in state/city legislative/executive bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A branch of the federal bureaucracy would oversee all elections. Furthermore, another branch (of the federal bureaucracy) would be responsible for continuously polling the levels of satisfaction constituents had for their tyrants. Falling below a certain percentage, say 25% approval, would trigger an automatic re election for the tyrants position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the difference in behavior, and “level of sophistication” between the chinese politburo and us congress partially inspired this line of thought (I think there are real problems with the chinese system though, though I must also admit it seems a bit opaque in operation to me (e.g. [3 ups 3 downs wtf?]: [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elections_in_China]), from what I can tell higher levels of government ultimately determine who is nominated to run for lower levels, which seems like a horrible idea to me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically I think the system of tyrants would lead to an aversion to the kinds of political radicals that make for appealing representatives under the current system, which is all about bargaining power in committee. A tyrant would also be able to design much more cohesive policy than a committee, and actually, legitimately, experiment and measure the results and reverse course if it doesn’t work out, something almost impossible in the current system since you have to brainwash your followers into a morality play every time you want to get something done. Initially there might be some bad outcomes, but good outcomes would replicate while bad ones died out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, smaller committee = more accountable and more ownership. Anything over 20ish starts to sort of turn on this undesirable mob behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly you might say, this decreases representation. I talked to my parents and they could not even NAME their representative in the state house of reps. A name is far from familiarity. Similarly they voiced the opinion that all that mattered was the political party of their representative… A bit of teaching to the test phenomena, doomed to result in bad outcomes. If the state was run by a tyrant everyone would know them and the policy decisions associated with them, everyone would have a more subtle opinion than just, “he’s a republican so we voted for him”. Similarly for everyone else in the proposed system - in this way the system would actually INCREASE the extent to which the electorate was represented by their government, by getting rid of this sort of paradox of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with those changes, I would also, sort of, eliminate capital cities. Gathering all the federal reps in one place would be too much of a liability. Congress/senate would act more like a distributed corporation e.g. automattic (people behind wordpress). Most federal communication would be done over asynchronous, recordable channels, and while I’m fantasizing, bills would be drafted using git as source control and hosted on github to see how the bills changed over time and what was considered XD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also probably quite a few details I haven’t thought through, or I’m not sure on the optimal approach, e.g. who gets to be on the ballot in the election of tyrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One change I would make to the court system is to give people the option to opt into receiving a random verdict, or semi random computer generated verdict, in some cases. I think this could potentially increase efficiency whilst maintaining the same level of “justice” for some legal issues. I haven’t looked into this too deeply however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also you could probably use some kind of block chain combined with rsa public key cryptography to run your geographically distributed election (maybe just distribute something like a yubi key to everyone once a year or something) and then in a separate process, poll people on how they voted to detect if a hack might have occurred.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Thinking a bit about what my fantasy form of government (I used to be a fan of direct democracy) nowadays would be, here it is:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Freedom Party</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/01/01/Freedom-Party.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Freedom Party" /><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/01/01/Freedom-Party</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/01/01/Freedom-Party.html">&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &amp;lt;section&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div id=&quot;title&quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;The Freedom Party: A New Set of Axioms for a Radically Different Libertarianism&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NotBrianZach/blog/issues&quot;&amp;gt;Comment or ask a question&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NotBrianZach/blog/fork&quot;&amp;gt;Suggest an addition (if I include it, will give credit if desired)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span class=&quot;credits left&quot;&amp;gt;Author(s): &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NotBrianZach&quot;&amp;gt;NotBrianZach&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      Libertarianism is unique amongst popular modern political philosophies in that all of it's positions and policy recommendations
      are derived from a single core principle or axiom: the non aggression principle.
      &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-aggression_principle&quot;&amp;gt;&quot;The non aggression principle asserts aggression is always an
        illegitimate encroachment upon another individual's life, liberty, or property.&quot;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
      So essentially pure libertarianism tries to limit government aggression. However governments by their very nature must use
      physical force as well as the threat of force, so despite it's clarity of vision, it seems like a non starter, to be basically
      incompatible with the whole notion of government. Moderate libertarians must under the current scheme compromise their own morale compass
      in order to function. I would argue your compass needs tuning if you know it consistently points 20 degrees off of north, and
      must use that fact to navigate.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      In this essay I try to derive a new set of axioms for libertarianism from a mathematical model (borrowed from computer science) of the way people make choices.
      Then I attempt to practically apply the model in the creation of a simple political philosophy and subsequently,
      the development and after the fact justification of, an individualized policy platform.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        The government exists to maximize the amount of Freedom its citizens have.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Freedom is subtle.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        A person is more Free when they have
        more choices available to them, the person is aware of those choices,
        and the choices are realistic choices to make under any system of values that is consistent
        with the continued existence of the rest of the human species.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        The government does not exist to maximize the total number of available choices,
        it exists to maximize the total amount of Freedom.
        Giving someone with 2 available choices one more choice increases Freedom more than giving
        someone with 100 available choices one more choice.
        See &amp;lt;a href=&quot;#footnoteModel&quot;&amp;gt;footnote&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for some ideas on how this could be mathematically formalized.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        One could imagine the government imprisoning the populace in a
        series of giant cages, like rats, and continuously offering up a panel of differently
        colored buttons, one of which delivers food, one an electric shock, and one doing nothing,
        with the buttons' effects assigned randomly. In this artificial scenario or one like it,
        the prisoners/citizens could be presented with an artificially high number of &quot;choices&quot;. However these
        &quot;choices&quot; do not provide very much Freedom. High quality choices have several properties
        that these do not. For one thing, nested choice, being able to choose what choices
        you make, is higher &quot;quality&quot; choice than non-nested choice. Freedom implies at least
        some nested choice. Freedom also implies that the sequences of choices people are
        presented with are not a closed loop. Offering the same sequence of choices over
        and over again with no way of escaping the cycle is not Freedom. The last property
        of choices that produce Freedom, is that they seem significant to the person making
        them.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Finally, one could imagine a society where everyone has a large number of
        nested, non-cyclical, seemingly significant choices available to them. However,
        they are all offered the same choices; the government has succeeded in imposing
        a single uniform philosophy across the entire population.

        Therefore the model must also have an &quot;anti-infantilization&quot; factor; we assume that
        reasonable adults will find different choices significant, though popularity is partially used to
        determine the weight given to a particular choice, at some point, the availability or continued existence of less common choices
        should be weighted very strongly.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        In summary, the maximally Free society is one where as many philosophies as possible, with
        some weight given to popularity, can all find as many choices as possibe, and nested choices, to make
        that seem significant and do not force the chooser to repeat them cyclically.

        It is the job of the individual to develop a personal philosophy to constrict the number of available
        choices for themselves and thus avoid the pitfalls of human psychology when facing large numbers of choices.
        Without the availability of choices outside of an individual's philosphical or ethical framework however,
        personal growth would be impeded. Thus in the absense of an obviously right philosophy, the ideology of Freedom
        (out of all possible political philosophies) is the one most likely to lead to a Hitchiker's Guide to the Galaxy esque
        &quot;computation of the meaning of life&quot; by a large number of individual agents.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        Responsibilities
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        If you agree that the government's purpose is to maximize Freedom, then
        you are a Freedom Party member.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        The first and only distinguishing responsibility held in common by Freedom party members
        is to think about and define what their responsiblities are as a Freedom party member.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        As a Freedom Party member, here's my game plan:
        &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
                To me, a Freedom Party member maintains their own platform, a series of policy prescriptions
        which they believe, after reflection, are most important for maximizing Freedom in their society.
            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
                To me, a Freedom Party member follows politicians for whom they can vote, whom they believe
        may implement policies from their platform, or policies important for Freedom more generally.
            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
                 To me, a Freedom Party member votes for the politician whom they believe will maximize Freedom
        in any given race, and who has a good chance of winning (necessary to actually maximize Freedom).
            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
                To me, a Freedom Party member communicates: they communicate to the politician for whom they voted
                why they voted for them and when they are pleased or displeased with political actions,
                and they communicate with other Freedom Party members to come up with
                and implement platforms that create more Freedom.
            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
                To re-iterate, in my opinion, a Freedom Party member should work on, think about, and update their platform,
                to make their platform more in line with the hypothetical, abstract, maximally Freedom
                inducing Freedom party platform.
            &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;
        My Personal Conception of the Policy Platform, in no particular order
    &amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        The two types of political policy are domestic and foreign.
        Foreign policy is simple: realpolitik, with a deference to expanding Freedom in situations
        where out of the available decisions, the decision that expands the power of the representative
        state is ambiguous.
        Other states are assumed to be &quot;rational&quot; actors that strive to maximize their own power so they can
        achieve their own ends. Thus in order to ensure Freedom in the representative state, one must
        play by the same rules.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        For domestic policy, in the current political system in the U.S as of this writing, maintaining the
        status quo is the goal, while expanding the amount
        of personal Freedom through the following projects.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        1. Shrink the overall tax-burden (on Freedom) of government
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
       &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
           There are a large number of ways to accomplish this without threatening Freedoms
           that the government
           protects, an example of a bad policy move would be eliminating food stamps, since
           forcing people to earn money to pay for basic necessities eliminates Freedom
           (and possibly life) for many people,
           such as those who are intellectually/physically/socially incapable of acquiring jobs.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          The single most important thing that can be done to shrink the tax burden of government is to automate
          (with computers)
          as many government functions as possible. Over the long term, say 50 years,
          my personal opinion is that most of it will turn
          out to be automateable. If a computer can play go, a computer can evaluate the merit of business licenses,
          especially as the amount of data available digitally expands.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          This is something that needs to be actively pursued, because the government does not face competitive
          pressure as immediately and clearly as businesses do.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          One thing that someone unfamiliar with the internals of a computer may be unaware of is just how many possibilities
          computer savvy opens up when paired with even a mild amount of curiosity and imagination. Real fundamental computer skills
          are more transferable than skills for the tasks they automate, by defintion the programmer is capable of doing more with their job skills
          than the accountants whom they replace; the programmer is more free.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          In some cases, this may require additional government legislation.
          For instance, irs audits could probably be mostly digitized; it might be much easier to do this after phasing out paper money.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;
          Save money by spending money; refusing to defer costs aka the will to spend
        &amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          Ultimately, after saving money and paying off debt (in the United States, the federal government has a different debt
          &quot;structure&quot; than local and state governments, so whether or not the federal government should pay off
           debt, or how much to pay off, is something for economists to debate), taxes can be lowered across the board.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          While we wait for our digital irs auditors,
          we can increase funding for the IRS until the return on the dollar is 1 dollar out to 1 dollar in.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
            Implement a universal toll road system. Every car could be tracked via mandatory gps, and a fee charged based on
            miles traveled * density of traffic in a given mile (more of an integral than multiplication).
            This could eliminate most traffic jams and the associated costs. It would also be able to track down hit and runs,
            and potentially eliminate the need for most traffic cops. It would probably be cheapest to just subcontract development
            out to google or apple. If this sounds a little Orwellian, it should be noted that the aforementioned companies already
            track a large numbers of vehicles via smartphones; this is how their &quot;maps&quot; applications
            make estimates of the traffic along a stretch of road:
            by tracking the speed at which your smartphone is moving.
            Once cars are autonomous they will most likely already have this ability built in, then it would be a comparatively
            simple matter of developing software.
            If road maintenance is paid for using this fee then cars will no longer be massively implicitly subsidized by the government,
            which is currently the case and a bad move from an urban planning perspective; it doesn't make sense to take the train because
            we built all these roads and pay for them without realizing it, when government subsidizes one form of transportation it distorts
            incentives and reduces choice. Even buses could be forced to pay this fee to make the cost of maintenance explicit in department budgets.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
            Increase funding for preventative burns of forestland until a reasonably sophisticated model shows
            that the return on the dollar is 1 dollar out to 1 dollar in.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;
          Reduce the burden of taxes on Freedom by shifting tax burden around
        &amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          The government should guarantee all citizens a basic income. This should be designed to pay for bare necessities.
          It should cover the median cost across all states for food (median cost of food for an adult),
          shelter (rent for a bedroom and bathroom, incuding electricity and water bills),
          discretionary expenses like toothpaste, clothing, shoes, toilet paper, etc.,
          and daily tranportation via bus, and be pegged to price indexes to follow inflation for the goods it is designed to guarantee.
          The government would mandate that everyone over a certain age receive a bank account or select one of their bank accounts
          as their &quot;government&quot; bank account. At the beginning of every month, a deposit would automatically be made. Income from the
          basic income would count towards income taxes. You would not receive the basic income while in jail.
          A basic income will be increasingly necessary as the economy becomes more automated. Re-training can take a long time,
          and not everyone will be able to re-train.
          With a basic income, minimum wage laws can be eliminated:
          this increases the number of tasks people can choose to do; and with a basic income they won't be coerced
          (though it might feel coercive to some to not be able to pay for tv or a smartphone,
          and not live in the most expensive cities, government promotion of freedom has to recognize the reality that
          we do not live in a post scarcity society, government can not make magic happen and give everyone all possible choices,
          trying to do so would result in a soviet style regime which ultimately fails to deliver as much choice as one where
          markets dictate prices, markets are much more sensitive to what people consider significant than governments).
          A basic income can also replace social security and eliminate the administrative overhead
          and some of the wealth redistribution (richer people live longer, if people receive basic income throughout life it will be more equitable)
          involved in social security.
          &amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
          You may ask what about people with children? Will they be guaranteed an income for each of their children?
          No. Minors (anyone under 18) will not receive the basic income directly either. See &amp;lt;a href='#2'&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
          Also a side benefit of this is it should eliminate (involuntary) homelessness, which from what I understand, is actually
          more costly than providing housing.
          &amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
            Tax junk foods. Unhealthy foods, through the inducement
            of obesity, diabetes and other dieseases, eliminate
            many choices people have available such as the choice to ride a bike
            to work, run a marathon, have children, live a longer life (with more potential choices),
            etc. Simply by discouraging junk foods the government can increase revenue and the total amount
            of Freedom, and reduce costs, while keeping desert as an (expensive) option.
            Soft drinks, juices, and deserts, or anything with a certain sugar content (in terms of percent composition)
            would be easy targets. Other targets:
            carbs other than staples such as rice, bread, cereal. Red meat vs. white.
            Foods with an excess of salt content would be another (relatively easy) target, might be easiest
            to implement by just taxing salt itself (even though it's nutritionally necessary
            could easily pay for extra funding to food stamp programs, and possibly even change restaurant behavior in particular).
            It would probably work just like a sales tax, and would probably be quite severe, e.g. 30%.
            Another idea: it might be easiest/more practical just to create a (fairly exhaustive, and amendable) food 'white list',
            foods recognized as healthy, and just apply junk food tax to everything else.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          There should be different categories of captial gains taxes, aside from just long term
          and short term.
          Broadly, weight should be shifted from income taxes to capital gains taxes.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          Eliminate subsidies, and encourage free trade/reduce tariffs. Both are widely acknowledged by economists as basically good/a win win.
          Easier said than done because the benefits are more diffuse than the benefits of the opposite policies,
          which typically go to single interest groups.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;
          Reduce the burden of taxes on Freedom by reducing costs
        &amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;h5&amp;gt;
          Before we get into budget cuts, a small primer on military capability
        &amp;lt;/h5&amp;gt;
          The US has been known for the past 20 ish years as the world's last superpower.
          The key factor behind this designation are the capabilities of the US military,
          which are unique and up to this point exclusive to the United States.
          Basically, the U.S. can establish aerial dominance over, and subsequently establish
          an armored and infantry ground presence in, any location on earth in a matter of days
          or even hours. There are several key pieces of infrastructure that enable this capability.
          &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;The U.S aircraft carrier fleet: the U.S has 10 aircraft carriers (and 2 more under construction). By way of comparison,
              China has 1, with 1 under construction, India has 2, Spain 1, France 1, UK 0. It varies a bit depending on how you count.
              But the basic idea is there. The 10 US enterprise class carriers are bigger and much more capable than all the others, by the way.
              Having said that these carriers, which enable the US ability to project force, are also our greatest vulnerability.
              A single well placed missle, that would be very difficult to stop, might be all it takes to sink or disable a carrier.&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;US foreign relations and international base presence: the US maintains a series of military bases in countries all over the world.
            The US even held the infamous Guantamo military base in Cuba in a time period when Cuba was hostile to US interests.&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; Logstical capability: this covers everything from satellite infrastructure, to oil reserves and production capability,
            to battle tested supply chain management practices.&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; Experience: the US military and command chain has far more actual combat experience than any other military, due to
               aggressive foreign policy &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;h5 id=&quot;militaryPoliceDrones&quot;&amp;gt;
          Military/Police Cost Reduction
        &amp;lt;/h5&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          The US military (and police forces) can save major money, maintain current capabilites, and
          become more effective through a complete overhaul of every military (and police) branch around the concept of drone warfare (surveillance/enforcement).

          This overhaul would take advantage of the existing network of overseas american bases to
          provide the US military with a competitive advantage in one of the major limiting factors
          of a drone based military: network latency. Global presence also provides operating
          redundancy in low probability high risk scenarios for example a high altitude nuclear detonation,
          or e.m.p attack, might disable the network over the mainland, but with skynet (which we'll get to shortly)
          + underground silos/ sub carriers,
          the network, could quickly be re estabilshed over the affected area, with foreign bases providing redundancy to
          command and control of assets. So one could say drone warfare and
          American military capabilities/diplomatic position go together like peanut butter and chocolate, that is, well.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          The backbone of any drone military (police force) would be a network of suborbital command and control drone aircraft,
          essentially a group of interconnected, redundancy providing, high flying cryptograhically (indeed, the real backbone of the military would be cryptography)
          secured wifi hotspots. This network could also potentially be
          partially leased out to, for instance, commerical operators of future autonomous cargo ships,
          who, just like the military, would need infrastructure to guarantee connectivity on the open ocean
          (as well as various other commerical interests that would require the same capability).
          Something along this line:
          &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spacesafetymagazine.com/spaceflight/sub-orbital/suborbital-satellites/&quot;&amp;gt;
            http://www.spacesafetymagazine.com/spaceflight/sub-orbital/suborbital-satellites/
          &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
          A good name might be... skynet.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          Infantry (and traffic cops and swat teams) can be replaced with quadcopters (or even, with machine learning perhaps, smaller single or double rotor drones).
          One could imagine various sizes of drones, from small, fast, maneuverable, and short lived combat drones,
          &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sFHRcW6qnvo&quot;&amp;gt;
          https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sFHRcW6qnvo
          &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
          to longer battery life slower, observation drones, to perhaps helicopter sized carrier drones, which might be able to
          drop off charging stations for their smaller brethren, ferry large numbers of smaller drones into battle, or pack serious firepower or
          relatively more armor, much like an apache attack helicopter of today
          [except deadlier in every way since there's no need for a cockpit and all the attendant machinery (no there is no need for police depts to have
          apache attack helicopter equivalents...)].
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          No more dead soldiers (cops). Occupations (patrolling) would incur less
          innocent casualties since drones don't need to ensure their own survival. Non-domestic [e.g. embassy] Suicide bombing could be pretty much eliminated
          as decreased physical presence [from fewer support staff and ground troops] means more resources to harden existing infrastructure against
          such attacks [also with the help of drones, of course].
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          Fighter jets can be replaced with the drones we are already familiar with: predators and their ilk.
          Drones are signifcantly cheaper to produce than a manned jet.
          Drones can perform maneuvers and accelerations that would kill a pilot.
          Drones are much easier to maintain and less prone to failure since they have a lot fewer moving parts. [no human machine interface].
          Ships can be replaced with drone ships that require greatly reduced [and remote] crews and aircraft carriers can be replaced
          with drone carriers which don't require runways
          [drones aren't bothered by high g forces, can be launched out of cannons or slingshots].
          Without the need to devote ship space to cafeterias, internal lighting and ac and whatnot, such ships
          might be able to operate for significantly longer periods of time without having to refuel,
          or carry a signifcantly larger number of aircraft, or deploy more aircraft simultaneously, or have a lower profile or even all four.
          One could even imagine drone carriers also capable of temporarily acting as submarines, dramatically reducing vulnerability.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          All of this would need to be done in phases of course, and it is already happening [and if the US doesn't modernize, the Chinese or Russians
          {or maybe Google or Facebook, both are working on suborbital internet delivery drones} will].
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          So what does this mean for the present political reality?
          It means eliminating [or cutting as much funding as possible] for the [disastrous] joint strike fighter program, and other manned jet programs.
          Cutting funding for railguns. [in the future funding might be re instated,
            as high velocity kintetic weaponry like a railgun might be a good counter against a foreign adversaries skynet, but right now there's no obvious payoff]
          Increasing funding for the development of drones of various kinds.
          Cutting funding for future soldier programs, stopping all r&amp;amp;d around human infantry
          [examples: no more armor research, no more sidearm research, no more headset research, no more exoskeleton reserch].
          Cutting funding for r&amp;amp;d around manned ships.
          Slowly introducing drones into combat roles.
          Making federal drone network capabilities available to local police departments at no cost.
          For instance we should experiment with deploying weaponized quadcopters e.g. to afghanistan, or in raids on ISIS
          [quite possibly this has already happened and they didn't tell us about it (or I am simply not up to date with the news cycle)].
          (police drones don't need to have weapons, but could summon weaponized ones if neccessary,
          to be clear, there would be a policeman flying the copter, but they would not be physically present e.g. at a traffic stop, so they would not be physically at risk or
          capable of violently abusing their authority, and therefore no police brutality, and if the job has physical risk removed from it,
          it will be cheaper to recruit people to do it, as well as to pay insurance premiums (this, once again, requires omnipresent network access)).
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

        &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
          There would be and are quite a few engineering challenges around this:
          how to get skynet orbiters aloft to the desired altitude [maybe a multi stage takeoff].
          how to deal with jamming devices [consider that the sun bombards the planet with em waves,
          mostly on visible/infrared/ultraviolet, yet we can still see on that same portion of spectrum just fine]
          software coordination and orchestration challenges, etc.
          but ask any of the relevant experts and I'm confident they will answer that
          any given component is quite doable. We just need to embrace the changes
          that are already happening, recognize pragmattic realities,
          and make conscious and thoughtful decisions about how we do so, instead
          of acting out of reflex.
        &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3 id='2'&amp;gt;
        2. Educate people
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Real education increases Freedom by making people aware of what they are capable of,
        what opportunities are available in the world.
        Childcare with educational value should be available 24/7, 365 days a year. This maximizes
        parent's Freedom, while ensuring the future intellectual Freedom of children regardless
        of their parent's financial or emotional state.
        Previous testing standards would initially be kept in place as requirements,
        and raised if the system improves.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        One of the educational systems biggest problems, especially in the United States of America, is Goodhart's law.
        &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://sports.vice.com/en_us/article/moreyball-goodharts-law-and-the-limits-of-analytics&quot;&amp;gt;https://sports.vice.com/en_us/article/moreyball-goodharts-law-and-the-limits-of-analytics&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        In order to counter this phenomenon, which in my opinion has come to dominate k-12 education in particular,
        We need to come up with a broader range of metrics to assess children's educational development and ranking.
        Here's some ideas:
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;educational velocity: the rate at which a child is improving/learning or demonstrating mastery of new topics, or even educational acceleration.&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;ability to retain: how much does the child retain after 1 month? 3 months? 6 months? a year? how well do they remember topics from 4 years ago?&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;performance relative to load: given how many hours/estimated difficulty of all school activiites they participate in, how well do they do?&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;performance relative to peers of similar background: how do children from low income households perform relative to their peers?&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
       &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        We already have the data to do this kind of analysis, we just lack the software.
        Assessment should be automated and standardized where possible (both, not one or the other).
        This enables broader and more complex assessment criteria, increases the freedom of students by reducing the coercive power teachers hold over them, and at the same
        time, teachers are freed up to do things other than grade, like help students understand why they got something wrong.
        Since helping someone involves interaction with another person, there are necessarily more choices involved than when
        grading, which is often simple and repetitious. Freedom is increased for both parties, and the
        relationship becomes more of an alliance and less adversarial and domineering.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Lectures should be offloaded from teachers to pre-recorded video,
        students should have the choice to stop on or repeat a portion of a lecture, while under the supervision and guidance of a teacher
        who could help students stay on task (though for the record, 5 minute breaks every 20 minutes or so are necessary to actually hold attention, breaks which the teacher might be able to participate and guide in a productive and positive way/ensure that breaks don't acquire an environment that is emotionally hostile),
        instead of force feeding information.&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;

        Online (software) markets (imagine something like uber or airbnb) could then be constructed to allow
        teachers to choose which classes they want to teach. If no teacher wanted to teach a class, pay would be increased until someone filled the role.
        Teaching requirements and licensing systems would need to be scaled back or eliminated entirely.
        Certification only needs to ensure three things: the teacher knows the material, the teacher is not predatory, and the teacher maintains order.
        So in order to teach a class a teacher would have to take a test, one measuring knowledge of, and ability to teach material, and
        the other their social ability to teach at that grade level, as well as a background check,
        the social test should be a short, one to three day affair in one or more real classrooms and done under the supervision of a previously qualified teacher who is given
        a list of scorecard to grade the prospecive teacher on, as well as the ability to comment on the candidate, and comments would persist on their profile for a period of time.
        just as airbnb relies on social media profiles and reviews to authenticate people;
        the teacher with the best overall applicalble test scores could fill the role for any given class.&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;

        Students should have more choice in how to meet the basic requirements of their education,
        though there should be a minimum mandatory level of performance on tests, which would be coupled with attendance requirements,
        students should be able to choose
        when they go to school. A student/nightowl who can barely even wake up at 7 am shouldn't be forced to.&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;

        Students should be free to proceed at their own pace irrespective of age.
        Eliminate the concept of &quot;grades&quot;, if students can graduate high school
        before the age of 18 they should be provided with free community college
        and then university if necessary, until they reach the age of 18.&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Essentially, schools should be much more dynamic in adjusting to demand.
        Children that have parents that love them shouldn't be raised by government bureaucrats,
        to the extent that it is possible for their parents to raise them, they should.
        In the proposed system there is no doubt this is a conscious choice on the part of the parent,
        something not assured by the current system.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Everyone should have internet access available to them through the local library.
        More library funding where/if appropriate.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3 id='3'&amp;gt;
        3. Freedom in matters of one's own biology
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        A potential mother should be free to choose whether to carry a child to term until the child
        is cognizant. Not necessariy self-aware (very difficult to prove/define) but aware (also difficult to define, current
        federally imposed limits are probably acceptable, 100 or even 10000 nerve cells are probably not 'aware' when a
        child or adult has billions, and even a rat has about 200 million neurons). Though personally I think even rats are aware
        to some extent and possibly even capable of a degree of emotion. Studies have shown both rats and chickens are capable of empathy.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Sex education is important. Abstinence only education often impinges on intellectual Freedom,
        by making people unaware of potential consequences of the choices they may make, which may impinge on future Freedom.
        Condoms, iuds, and other safe sex &quot;tools&quot; should be made freely available by the government.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Assisted suicide should be legalized.
        One might think that allowing someone to kill themselves reduces freedom since it reduces
        lifespan, and thus the total number of choices an individual confronts.
        However throughout a person's life, suicide is always an option, something true
        of almost no other choice. Taking away, or trying to take away, that option
        thus reduces Freedom more than almost any other individual choice.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      Biological research into topics like genome editing and stem cells, which could give people more choice in matters of their biology,
      far from being banned or suppressed should be encouraged and in promising cases, funded with government grants.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      Thought experiment: does this mean the government should fund research into sex change surgery?
      Short Answer: no.
      Long answer: not while people are still dying of cancer and getting older (getting alzheimers, etc.).
      But think, right now we see gender as a sort of &quot;God-given&quot; trait,
      an integral and immutable part of your personality (funnily enough ethics, friendships, family ties,
      all seem quite naturally changeable in comparison to the foundational identity of gender or race).
      In the future though, and in some cases, today, gender will
      actually be something assigned to you by your parents. Imagine you are a heterosexual Chinese male, and in
      your generation there are 50% more men than women. You want to have a life partner, someone to share
      the ups and downs (and also sexual intimacy) with, however you are also shorter than average and balding.
      Online dating combined
      with male cultural standards mean that every woman that is available is inudated with literally
      hundreds of courtship offers a month. In short, it's not going to happen.
      In fact, it's physically impossible for all men in that situation to find a (monagomous) partner. Does it
      really seem ridiculous, in that situation, that someone might want to change their gender
      (or maybe just grow some hair and a few feet taller (if you can change that why not your gender?)), to reverse
      a decision that their parents made? Well that's a slightly exaggerated version of what many men will
      in fact experience in the coming generation in China. (insert joke about sexless marriages here).
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        4. Eliminate, break up, or make noncompetitive monopolies where those monopolies threaten Freedoms
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Property taxes must exist, and be protected for this reason.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;315&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;
        src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ztd9m71Jc-Y&quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      It is important that software should be free. See the &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/gnu/manifesto.en.html&quot;&amp;gt;gnu manifesto&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.

        All software produced and used by the government and not related to national security should be open source and licensed under
        a copyleft license.

        Government funded research should only be published in open access journals, with exceptions made for things like national security.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3 id='5'&amp;gt;
        5. Legalization
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Drugs and prositution should be legalized, regulated, and taxed, though, like
        gambling, geographically confined (people should be able to choose what kind of
        &quot;moral climate&quot;/what the local ethical standards are where they live, as much as possible anyway (see proposal number &amp;lt;a href='12'&amp;gt;12&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; )).
        People should, as much as possible, be able to have control over their own biological functioning, see proposal number &amp;lt;a href='3'&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        6. The State should have a monopoly on the use of violent force, and minimize
        coercive use of that force
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Coercive violence impinges Freedom. The state should have a monopoly on
        violence that is counterbalanced and regulated by the structure of power
        as exercised by the state.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      Body Cameras. Police should all wear body cameras.

      Even farther than that, though, any government official who could conceivably
      use violence to coerce on a day to day basis, should be monitored on some level.
      Similarly, teachers should wear body cameras (or maybe just have classroom cameras) while in contact with
      students, though footage would only be made available to some subset of school administrators,
      or after due process in the courts. All of this would be archived for some set period.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Gun control:
        &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/17/opinion/sunday/some-inconvenient-gun-facts-for-liberals.html&quot;&amp;gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/17/opinion/sunday/some-inconvenient-gun-facts-for-liberals.html&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
        Violence is a coercive tool and should be regulated by the government.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        7. Obamacare
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Actually Obamacare does not directly impinge on Freedom since fines for not paying are only deducted
        from tax refunds.
        From the perspective of economic theory it should reduce overall costs (and increase overall Freedom) by bringing
        together fragmented markets and creating a more competitive environment.
        In fact we can dramatically expand this basically good idea, in a way that, on the surface,
        dramatically reduces choice, but in fact dramatically expands the total number of
        realistic choices.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        The idea is this: a unified, government mandated job market.
        It will have initial technical difficulties,
        all software projects do.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Legally, all jobs would have to be posted to a government website,
        and acquired (the job offer accepted and details (like pay) finalized) through the same website. This could actually lower costs
        for a lot of companies. A tidal wave of resume spam could be prevented
        by making applicants answer a series of quiz questions/captchas/other techniques about/provided by the company, or via other techniques.
        Ultimately it could greatly reduce hiring costs for employers.
        Automated tools could be built around the standardized interface and data
        job applicants could be required to have in their profiles.
        Might help in automating parts of people's/companies tax returns as well.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Plus, the government could collect data on job postings. Since all hires
        have to go through the website (including govt hires), the government would have a (close to) perfectly complete (along with business filings) data
        set on job growth, and what industries are in demand. The government could then use this
        data to extrapolate demand for many if not most professions.
        A unified job market, combined with publicly available, prominently displayed
        government projections for job growth in different areas along with current enrollment in training programs,
        would give individuals a much better idea of exactly what kind and how many jobs are available.
        Each job posting could also show how many applications had been submitted for it.
        The goal would be to prevent colleges from selling kids degrees under the pretense they will
        be able to get a job with them when that is not actually the case.
        Huge student debt burdens greatly reduce Freedom, and one is more free to make real choices when informed.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Normally the government can't be trusted to do a good job with complex technology issues govt bureaucrats are unfamiliar with.
        However for high visibility projects, the initial release might be bungled but, eventually it will be brought up to standard.
        Where there's a will there's a way; the best way to ensure something works is to make it necessary for it to work.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      At first the job market would be restricted to only a certain subset of actual jobs,
      e.g. those that are 40 hours or more a week, and only for government positions,
      and gradually expanded as the system improved (assuming it improved, if it didnt,
      well then it's a failure... it happens).
        However as lessons are learned from the design of that unified market, it might also be possible to unify the part time work
        and contractual work markets. These might call for slightly different approaches, for instance a contractual work market may be based around
        some kind of &quot;blockchain&quot; technology. Indeed these might not even be best or most appropriate ways to divide or categorize the different
        parts of the job market which require different solutions. But the end goal is the same: provide a single source of truth for
        job/contract/work availability, wages, and worker supply, and a more competitive, unififed, market.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        8. Set demographic targets and tax breaks/burdens for those raising children, and immigration policy appropriately
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Steady population growth, while the size of the population is sustainable given the available arable
        land, as Japan, China, and Europe are learning, is a very good way to guarantee economic growth, which provides more opportunites to citizens.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        It is particularly important to have young people if there are large numbers of retirees, or vice versa, as the experiences of african nations show.
        A balance in political power between demographic groups helps stabilize a democracy, and a balance in the working age population, children, and retirees
        helps stabilize the economy.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Under realpolitik immigration of adults is an obvious win since the host nation essentially
        steals the cost of educating and raising immigrants from the source nations.
        Setting aside the cynical lens of realpolitik for a moment, youth unemployment in poorer countries with burgeoning young popultations
        will be a serious problem in the coming years, even as the populations of developed nations contract. Immigration, like free trade, would benefit everyone.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        9. Electoral reform
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Fix gerrymandering. This gives more people actual choices to make.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;315&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;
      src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kUS9uvYyn3A&quot; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Provide voters more choice in elections, eliminate first past the post voting.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;315&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;
      src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Y3jE3B8HsE&quot; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
       10. The environment
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sustainability&quot;&amp;gt;
            https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sustainability
        &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
        Sustainability is important for ensuring Freedom in the long term.
        When an informed person knows it's better for their health if they don't go outside today
        because of air pollution, then Freedom has been impinged, not just for them, but
        for everyone in their community.
        Gasoline/coal should be taxed as much as is politically tolerable.
        Current emissions/environmental standards in the United States should be protected and enforced.
        The national park system should also be protected.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
       11. Shouldn't lying be legal, aren't most possible statements also lies?
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      Lying is already legal in many circumstances.
      Forms of lying where the false information affects the well being of the recipient on the other hand, are often illegal,
      and should remain that way if the government wants to promote Freedom.
      People operating with bad information have less Freedom since they are unaware of the
      true nature of the choices they make.
      Most lies are simply nonsense and not threatening, e.g the sky is neon pink; hopefully it isn't or something is very very wrong.
      Examples of harmful and coercive lies: Calling in a bomb threat is illegal; it coercively forces people into acting in a way that they would otherwise not,
      and endangers life.
      Cigarrete advertising is illegal; it misrepresents what a cigarrete is, potentially reducing people's lifespans,
      and getting them hooked on a coercive chemical. And it should remain that way.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3 id='12'&amp;gt;
      12. The legal system should be hierarchicaly structured to give people more choice
      12.a. On issues with both high voter turnout and a well informed public, choices should be made
      by vote.
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        People should, as much as is possible/practical,
        be able to choose what type of government they live under. This is already accomplished
        through a tiered system of governance: local laws diverge from state laws diverge from federal laws.
        This isn't necessarily about states rights: indeed the granularity with the most choice is at the county level.
        As a practical matter however, one has to balance the additional complexity of such structures against
        the need to keep government as small as possible.
      &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        It is unfortunately not completely true that people get to choose where they live.
        For instance, children do not and could not choose where they live
        (though if there was 24 hour schooling and no show parents, maybe a process could be made available to them
        so that they could choose to transfer from one place to another). Many people have financial and other obligations
        which makes it very difficult or costly to move. So we must also balance giving a portion of the population
        more choice with more concentrated coercive power being given to a smaller group of individuals. Under the current system there are less
        checks on local abuses of authority
        (the system of checks and balances, senate vs. congress vs. president vs. supreme court, is better integrated at federal level than state or local level),
        and it is harder to build checks into local governments.
        Just thinking about the pre-existing elegance of the system endears great respect for the leaders of colonial America.
        Of course part of it might just have been luck.
      &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        An example policy:
        In some &quot;commercial&quot; districts, real estate owned by non-profits could be opened up to property taxes.
        This would create choice for those who are non-religious for instance, since local property owned by religious organizations would be taxed.
        Whether or not a district is commercial or non-commercial would be decided by the people that live there, not a government bureaucrat.
        Or the flip-side: dispute resolution thru informal sharia &quot;courts&quot; could be legal in one county and illegal the next county over.
        See also the previously mentioned legalization of controlled substances or prostitution, in proposal &amp;lt;a href=&quot;#5&quot;&amp;gt;5&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.
      &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        Feel free to fork and write your own manifesto, preferably one ensuring Freedom!
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        Not to be associated with the &quot;American Freedom party&quot;, or any actually existing political organization
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
        Postscript
    &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      But what about the paradox of choice? Doesn't having more choices make people less happy?
      People become overwhelmed by choice when they're at the grocery store and they have to choose between 400 brands
      of nutritionally identical cereals and 30 kinds of indistinguishable processed meats. We are weighting more
      than just the number of choices someone has available.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        This notion of Freedom  is just a model, an
        approximation of reality. All of currently understood theoretical physics is also just
        an approximation, albeit a very good one, good enough to allow us to build
        spaceships and computers and microwaves, all of the conveniences of modern life.
        Hopefully with a better approximation of how governments should relate to people, we will be able
        to build better governments.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Freedom seems like a good candidate for being the most fundamental human right.
        Not that it should replace human rights, sometimes you have to stick a stake in the ground and say,
        I am not going to budge. One could reasonably base one's entire platform on that principle, and end
        up as a traditional libertarian (whatever that is).
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        You might argue that it's very difficult to know what would increase or decrease Freedom, that it could be used to justify anything,
        (and would probably take my set of policy prescriptions as evidence).
        Well, have you ever seen that one experiment with a jar full of marbles, where a crowd guesses how many marbles are in the jar?
        Though each guess might be wildly divergent from the actual number of marbles, if you take the average, it's
        typically very close if not exact.
        With many different people trying earnestly to produce platforms that increase Freedom, the average
        should be close to the platform that actually increases Freedom.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p id=&quot;footnoteModel&quot;&amp;gt;
        &quot;Freedom&quot; can be formalized (represented with symbolic logic) with the computer science notion of a
        directed graph/&quot;non-deterministic finite state automata&quot; (fancy word for a simple concept).
        &amp;lt;img src=&quot;./images/diagram.png&quot; style=&quot;border:3px; border-radius:5px&quot;/&amp;gt;
        States, which are represented by circles, are characterized by what choices are available to them.
        Choices are represented by arrows. The number of choices can be weighted for quality through a &quot;choice&quot; score
        that can be computed by giving each arrow a weight, and summing over those weights,
        based on the number of &quot;child&quot; states (where each
        subsequent generation is given less weight than the previous one), how quickly
        those children become cyclical and how many are cyclical, and the perceived &quot;signficance&quot; of each choice to the chooser.
        In this model then, the 'Freedom Score' would be computed from a 'choice score' instead of directly from the number of choices.
        e.g. (and there is probably a better way to do it)
        freedom score = (choice score)/ (choice score + (constant value variable)), the constant valued variable could be adjusted to fine
        tune the balance in the model between giving many choices to few people or fewer choices to many people.

        Of course in real life people have many more choices and dynamically come up with new ones, however it's the thought that counts,
        and as a practical matter for any particular piece of legislation if you did want to come up with a quantitative argument you
        would try and enumerate the possible relevant states and transitions people might undergo.

        With a mathematical model in hand one could imagine new ways of enacting government policy. The government could, for example, set
        a target for wealth distribution, then leave it up to a program to dynamically adjust variables (like income tax rates) each year
        until the target is hit.
        Such a system would of course need to come with an off switch/failsafes. But perhaps techniques like that could be used to help solve the
        information asymmetry problem democratic societies face: there is too much information to process for every citizen to participate in
        every political discussion. Often times people will not even be aware of how elections or referendums might affect their daily lives.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        Technically one could debate which is a better model: deterministic finite state automata or
        non-deterministic finite state automata. I chose non-deterministic because they can
        represent more complex situations with less notation. Any non deterministic finite automata can
        be converted into/represented with a deterministic one.
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
        If you want or need help setting up a github repository/website, the author
        can be contacted for a screenshare via
        skype at zachary.abel1  (I'm afraid my sympathies for the gnu project run only skin deep, and don't want to share my email address)
        though if you take this offer you may be recruited to help explain git to other people,
        depending on demand
    &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">&amp;lt;section&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&quot;title&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;The Freedom Party: A New Set of Axioms for a Radically Different Libertarianism&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NotBrianZach/blog/issues&quot;&amp;gt;Comment or ask a question&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NotBrianZach/blog/fork&quot;&amp;gt;Suggest an addition (if I include it, will give credit if desired)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;hr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&quot;credits left&quot;&amp;gt;Author(s): &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NotBrianZach&quot;&amp;gt;NotBrianZach&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;</summary></entry></feed>